# Ivan Palmegiani, MSc

ivan.palmegiani@gmail.com | LinkedIn Account | GitHub Account

**Berlin - Germany** 

Further contacts available on request



### **Profile**

Scientist with strong analytical mindset and very good organization skills. Advanced technical capabilities developed over 5+ years working experience, and intensive training. Excellent communication skills. Team worker, also able to take charge of tasks individually. Highly motivated and positive towards challenges. Solution oriented and careful about details. Constructive critical thinker. Curious and eager to learn.

# **Expertise**

R coding | Python programming | Relational (geo)databases (SQL-PostGreSQL) | Geographic Information Systems (GIS) | Exploratory data analyses (EDA) | Hypothesis testing | Inferential and predictive modelling | Machine Learning (ML) | Time series analyses and forecast | Data visualization | Data reporting | Research

# Professional Experience

Freelance Data Scientist | Quantitative Analyst, June 2018 - Present

IZW - Leibniz Institute for Zoo and Wildlife Research

**PhD Candidate**, May 2014 - Jun. 2018 | **Research Assistant**, Apr. 2013 - Sept. 2013 Main goal: Investigating the mating system of freeranging cheetahs in central Namibia.

- Collected and analyzed long time series of geo-referenced and telemetry data with Kernel Density Estimation (KDE), Movement-based KDE (MKDE), Brownian Bridges Movement Models (BBMM), Local Convex Hulls (LoCoH), K-nearest neighbors algorithms (k-NN), Random-walks.
- Explored data and modelled environmental dynamics with linear and nonlinear regression models.
- Collected and analyzed presence-absence data via camera-trap surveys. Designed and maintained relational (geo)databases.
- Provided insights to stake-holders, team members, and scientific audiences through data reporting and visualization. Two to three scientific papers will be published.
- Coordinated data collection in the field, supervised volunteers.
- Organized scientific symposia.

CIBIO - Research Center in Biodiversity and Genetic Resources

Research Assistant, Dec. 2012 - Feb. 2013 | Research Technician, Feb. 2012 - Nov. 2012

Page 1/2 Resume - Ivan Palmegiani

Main goal: Investigate the spatial ecology of freeranging wolves, and predator-prey relationship in Peneda-Gerês National Park (PT).

- Collected and analyzed GPS telemetry and geo-referenced environmental data.
- Explored and modelled presence-absence in relation to environmental variables using linear and nonlinear regression models.
- Designed and maintained relational (geo)databases.
- Provided insights to stake-holders, team members, and scientific audiences, data reporting and visualization.

#### Department of Zoology and Evolutionary Genetics, University of Sassari

Research Technician, Nov. 2010 - Nov. 2011

Main goal: Investigate spatial distribution, reproductive success, and predator-prey relationship of freeranging wolves in Arezzo Province - Tuscany (IT).

- Collected geo-referenced environmental data.
- Collected and analyzed bio-acoustic data.
- Collected and analyzed presence-absence data via camera-trap surveys.

**Teaching experience**: lecturer on wildlife survey and monitoring methods.

### Education

**Master of Science (MSc)**, Jul. 2010 *Environmental science and natural resources management*, University of Sassari. Grade: 110/110 *cum Laude* 

Environmental modelling, statistical inference, advanced statistical theory, zoocenosis and wildlife conservation, wildlife management, genetics, plant conservation, environmental economics, systems ecology, landscape ecology, regional geology, sedimentology.

## Languages

English (IELTS certification level C1) • German (TELC certification level B1) • Italian (mother tongue) • Spanish (fluent) • Portuguese (fluent)

#### Hobbies and interests

Outdoor sports and activities such as climbing, bouldering, hiking, biking, canoeing, camping • Indoor gardening • Urban farming • DIY and Handicraft • Music and Arts • Cooking

Page 2/2 Resume - Ivan Palmegiani